<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://crtoomey.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://crtoomey.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-05-13T19:10:19+00:00</updated><id>https://crtoomey.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">SQL Injection Lab - Altoro Mutual</title><link href="https://crtoomey.github.io/blog/2024/sql-injection-lab/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SQL Injection Lab - Altoro Mutual"/><published>2024-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://crtoomey.github.io/blog/2024/sql-injection-lab</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://crtoomey.github.io/blog/2024/sql-injection-lab/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="disclaimer">Disclaimer</h2> <p>This lab was conducted for educational purposes as part of the Ethical Hacking and Penetration Testing course at SUNY Canton, using a deliberately vulnerable website designed for training. The focus of this lab is on SQL injection. The methods and techniques discussed in this blog post are intended solely for educational use and should not be applied to engage in illegal activities. Always obtain explicit permission before conducting penetration testing on any system.</p> <h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2> <p>For this ethical hacking lab, I was instructed to find 10 pairs of usernames and passwords to login into <a href="http://www.testfire.net/">Altoro Mutual</a>, a website that was designed to be vulnerable, using SQL injection (SQLi). This blog post details the approaches, methods, and process of completing this lab and also my thoughts on how to mitigate SQL injection vulnerabilities. I will also cover what my professor was actually expecting us to do, which will hopefully be as funny to you as it was for me when he told us.</p> <h2 id="first-approach">First Approach</h2> <h2 id="setbacks">Setbacks</h2> <h2 id="character-by-character">Character by Character</h2> <h2 id="lessons-learned">Lessons Learned</h2>]]></content><author><name>Colin Toomey</name></author><category term="tech"/><category term="hacking"/><category term="lab"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[this lab was a part of my Ethical Hacking and Penetration Testing course at SUNY Canton]]></summary></entry></feed>